{
    "id": "d65c7fdef3be4a61a0c658f7faf0ae74",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I …………………………….. him for a long time.",
            "description": "In sentences with since and for, we normally use the present or past perfect tense in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have known",
                "knew",
                "had known"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I was sorry when Janet moved to another city. We ……………………….. good friends since our childhood.",
            "description": "In sentences with since and for, we normally use the present or past perfect tense in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have been",
                "had been",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ……………………………. about six letters since morning.",
            "description": "In sentences with since and for, we normally use the present or past perfect tense in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have written",
                "had written",
                "wrote"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It is important that she ………………………….. me before she leaves.",
            "description": "In British English the structure with should is more common, whereas in American English subjunctives without should are more common.",
            "answers": [
                "should meet",
                "meet",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………………… more polite to him.",
            "description": "Should have been and ought to have been can be used to talk about unfulfilled past obligations.",
            "answers": [
                "should have been",
                "ought to have been",
                "must have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He insisted that he …………………………… heard.",
            "description": "In British English the structure with should is more common, whereas in American English subjunctives without should are more common.",
            "answers": [
                "be",
                "should be",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You ………………………………….. him an idiot – it really upset him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "should not call",
                "should not have called",
                "would not have called"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am sure I …………………………….. him before.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect for past events where we are thinking of a period of time continuing up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "have met",
                "met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I got caught in the rain and my coat …………………………….",
            "description": "The present passive often has the same meaning as the present perfect passive.",
            "answers": [
                "is ruined",
                "has been ruined",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The phone rang while I ……………………………. in the kitchen.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause will also be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Negatives oxygen atoms ……………………………….. positive hydrogen atoms.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "are attracted",
                "attract",
                "attracting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ………………………………. me any help.",
            "description": "The present perfect is commonly used with ever and never. ",
            "answers": [
                "never gave",
                "have never given"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}